翻译 kk
翻译 飞少爷
时间轴  Chenfan
两名英国情报官员 昨天从布达佩斯来到这儿
Two British Intelligence officers arrived last night from Budapest.
校对  Chenfan
你的人能不能对他们做些什么
I was wondering if your people might be able to do something about them?
后期  Chenfan
你是在寻求我的帮助吗
Are you asking me for my help?
趴下
Get down! Get down!
总监  Chenfan
有人想方设法杀我
Someone is going out of their way to try and kill me.
这里是我家 我问你答
You're in my house! Tell me everything I need to know.
若有意参与热门影视剧的字幕译制
让自己的名字出现在字幕开头
远鉴字幕组招新群 483552098
招募英语翻译 欢迎您的加入
不然我杀了你
Or you die.
欢迎关注 b站up主 远鉴字幕组
公众号 远鉴影视
微博 @远鉴字幕组v @远鉴的小跟班v
微博资源博主 @苏苏IFA
乔治·汉兹 他管理着一个狙击手的群聊
George Hands. He runs a sniper WhatsApp group.
-发我地址 我自己去  -我不是内鬼
- Text me the address. I'll go myself. - I'm not the mole, you know.
你当年能射出那样一枪吗
Could you have made that shot?
有一个人 亚历山大·杜根
There is one guy. Alexander Duggan.
你相信他跟你说的话吗
You believe everything he told you?
我也不确定
I don't know.
眼下 我只能选择相信
Right now all I can do is trust.
晚上六点开始 封锁整栋大楼
From 1800 the entire building is locked down.
不许任何人进出
No one gets in or out.
资流会改变这一现状
River is gonna change everything.
去死吧 暴君
Fuck you, you tyrant!
他在这里
He's in here somewhere.
封锁所有出口
Lock all the exits.
彼得
Peter?
你长了一张好人脸 拉斯穆斯
You've got a good man face, Rasmus.
赫尔曼德  阿富汗
目标在据点内
Target inside compound.
距离 1400米
Range 1,400.
1400米
1,400.
风偏值
Wind...
0.5
0.5.
开枪
Send it.
不是他
That's not him.
-快开枪 我们离开这个鬼地方  -不行 他胡子是白的
- Send it and let's get the fuck out of here. - No, his beard's white.
没人关心 达根 谁他妈会关心这个
No one cares, Duggan. No one gives a fuck!
-放倒他 别在这浪费时间  -那个人不是他 加里
- Just drop him so we can get out of this fucking. - That's not him, Gary.
-目标消失  -不是目标
- Target out of view. - It wasn't the target.
他彻底跑了
He's fucking gone.
我们还得等多长时间
How long are we gonna have to wait?
等多久都行
As long as it takes.
有些花朵
♪ Some flowers
从未绽放 不见天日
♪ Never get to bloom and see the day
有些花朵
♪ Some flowers
得过且过
♪ Are content to wish their lives away
有人崛起
♪ Some may rise
有人跌倒
♪ And some may fall
但唯有
♪ But only
你让
♪ You make
天堂般的美好
♪ Heaven
变得真实
♪ Seem it's true
唯有
♪ So, only
你能
♪ You can
告诉他们
♪ Tell them
真实的我
♪ This is who I am
改编自弗雷德里克·福赛斯的小说
真实的我
♪ This is who I am
没有欺骗
♪ No lie
看清
♪ Know that
真实的我
♪ This is who I am ♪
豺狼的日子
第一季 第八集
乌勒·达格·查尔斯遭遇未遂刺杀后
'Details are still murky following what appeared to be
很多细节仍未披露
an assassination attempt on Ulle Dag Charles...'
-是利奥诺拉  -接 免提
- It's Leonora. - Well, put her on speaker phone.
到底发生了什么事
What in God's name happened?
可以确认的是 那个突然冲出来的人不是我们雇的那个
'All I know is, the man who pulled that stunt wasn't our guy.'
泰迪 传闻说枪手是乌达查安保团队的一员 是真的吗
Teddy, is it true that the gunman was one of UDC's own security staff?
突发新闻 乌达查侥幸躲过枪击
乌达查很安全 他向全世界保证
UDC is safe. He wants to assure the world...
突发新闻 乌达查侥幸躲过枪击
-利奥诺拉 你这会儿在看新闻吗  -我看到了
- Leonora, are you seeing what we're seeing? - I am.
他不会容许邪恶势力阻止资流在28号发布
'He'll not allow sinister forces to prevent the launch of River on the 28th.'
连达格豪斯公司董事会都认为资流上市
'Is it true even the Dag Haus board believes River
对于世界经济是一场灾难 是否属实
will be a disaster for the world economy?
资流终将流淌
River will flow.
谢谢 采访结束
Thank you. Good night.
董事会 一群胆小怕事 没有骨气的马屁精
The board! Gutless, spineless, bunch of arselickers.
他们当然会听苏莱曼大圣人的 让资流发布
Of course they're going ahead if Saint Suleiman tells them to.
你怎么能让这种事发生 这种程度的安保完全他妈的不够
How could you let that happen? It's not fucking good enough.
所以 我们现在怎么办
'So, what are our options? Hm?'
要是这玩意儿发布了 我不如去农贸市场摆摊维生
Because if this thing launches, I may as well open a stall in a farmer's market.
-利奥诺拉 我们的杀手还能干活吗  -齐娜正在确认
- Leonora, is our guy still active? - Zina's trying to determine that now.
是吗 让她快点确认 好吗
Is she? Tell her to make the determination fast, would ya?
塔林是我们唯一的机会 他却失手了
Tallinn was our one chance and he missed!
我们在着手做了
We're on it.
距离资流发布还有一周 他还有机会
He still has a week until they release River.
一旦豺狼现身 我就去了解情况
As soon as the Jackal breaks cover, I'll find out what's going on.
齐娜 你不了解温斯罗普
You don't know Winthrop like I do, Zina.
失败会让他们感到危险
Failure threatens these men.
他们视败事者为草芥
And anyone associated with that failure is expendable.
他肯定在封锁之前就躲在这了
He must have hidden down there before the lockdown.
整整两天 真有耐心
Two days. That is some patience.
是啊
Yep.
那就是诺曼打印出来的枪
Ah, that'll be the gun Norman printed up.
港口 机场 边检都收到画像了
The ports, airports and border crossings have all got the e-fit.
看看豺狼做的这些前期准备
Look at all the planning the Jackal put into all this.
是啊 然后那个怪胎克里斯让他功夫全白费了
Yeah, then that fucking weirdo Chris ruined it for him.
他是搞极端宣言的狂热分子
He's one of those manifesto nutters.
开枪前还在社交媒体发文
Posted it on Facebook just before he took the shot.
-发了什么  -很长
- God, what's it say? - It's long.
一堆大写字母
Lots of random capital letters.
他想让大家相信 乌达查他们发布资流是为了自身利益
He wanted everyone to think that River was for their own good.
骗子 骗子 骗子 他想要信息
Liar, liar, liar. He wanted information...
我还是不理解
I still don't understand
你怎么能不知道这家伙是个信阴谋论的妄想狂
how you didn't know this guy was a conspiracy fantasist?!
他用不同账号匿名发的
He posted under different handles. Nothing in his own name.
你差点让一个狂热分子杀了乌勒
You allowed a fanatic to come this close to killing Ulle.
让他们立即滚蛋
They need to go. Now!
我明白您的意思 但豺狼仍然在逃
I fully understand, but the Jackal is still on the loose.
我现在不但要担心豺狼
The Jackal is no longer my only concern.
还要担心家里有人想杀我
I am worried about the people literally in my own house!
什么叫没有
What do you mean, nothing?!
没有符合画像的人
Well, nothing matches the e-fit yet.
他当时在那 肯定混在这些人中
We know he was there so he's gotta be one of these people!
不匹配
他不是他妈的鬼魂 不可能就这么消失了
He's not a fucking ghost, he can't just disappear!
这个人 和我们一样
This guy's...just like us.
他总有生理需求
He has needs.
要吃饭 会生病
He eats, he gets sick.
他去哪里休息
Where does he go to rest?
他向谁寻求帮助 谁照顾他
Who does he turn to? Who takes care of him?
我让你找的亚历山大·杜根的报告呢
Where's your report on Alexander Duggan?
马上发你更新版
Sending you the updated version now.
有点少吧
It's a bit thin, no?
他和他小队的报告属于二级绝密
Well, the file on Duggan and his unit is STRAP 2, so.
-什么  -这不合理
- What? - That doesn't make any sense.
二级绝密比机密还高两级
STRAP 2 is two levels higher than top secret.
这么说 杜根他们之前执行了某些任务
So Duggan and his unit must've done some things
军队和国防部都想掩盖住
that the Army and MoD...wanna keep covered up.
我们已经在这等了六个小时 杜根
Six hours we've been here, Duggan.
B2小队 车辆正在行进
Bravo Two. Vehicles in transit.
目标走出据点
Target coming out of the compound.
距离 1400米
Range 1,400.
1400米
1,400.
风偏值
Wind.
准星向左偏移0.4
0.4. Left to right.
偏移0.4
0.4.
开枪
Send it.
这是真正的考验
♪ It's the acid test
豺狼
今天很忙 没穿背心
♪ Got a busy day not wearing a vest
幻影
已习以为常
♪ It's all in a day... ♪
按倒他
Tackle him!
好 进球
Yeah! Get in!
换个方向都不会打了
Can't even tackle a different swing.
杜根 机会难得 别让我们失望
You're gonna have to convert that, Duggan. Don't let us down.
好啊
Yeah.
-这么好  -杜根 你最好分点给我们
- That's very kind. - I hope you're sharing that, Duggan.
当然 加里
Always, Gaz.
去吧 老大 把它贴上
Go on, then, boss, stick it on.
不该是我贴 只能他去贴
No, not me. There's only one man who should do this.
上吧 加里
Go for it, Gary.
杜根
Dugs! Dugs!
Dugs! Dugs! Dugs!
杜根
Dugs! Dugs! Dugs! Dugs! Dugs! Dugs!
你们这些小伙子有人想休息两天吗
So, I don't suppose any of you chaps fancy a couple of days R&R?
去塞浦路斯玩两天
Quick trip to Cyprus?
-休假两天  -太棒了
- Aki Arms? - Come on!
散会
Result!
干得漂亮 兄弟
Good job, man.
阿克罗蒂里  塞浦路斯
1400米
1400 metres!
见了鬼了 你怎么做到的 杜根
Fucking... How do you do that, Duggan?
你完全就是英国军队最强狙击手
Fuckin' best sniper in the entire British Army.
话虽如此 我还是挺你的
But I love ya.
你没我不行
Couldn't do it without me, though.
承认吧 我就是世界上最好的观测手
Admit it. I'm the best spotter in the world.
我成就你的伟大
I make you great.
不好意思
Excuse me.
-别冲动 加里  -不好意思
- Wait, Gary. - Sorry, sorry.
-加里 冷静点  -我没有恶意 好吗
- Gaz. Gaz. - I meant no offence, OK.
-抱歉  -我能请你们二位绅士喝一杯吗
- I'm sorry. - Can I buy you gentlemen a drink?
兄弟 这个问题的答案永远都是可以 买吧
Mate, the answer to that question is always gonna be yes, buy away!
好 再给他们上一轮 给我一杯
OK. Another round here, and one for me.
冷静点 兄弟
Keep it calm, buddy.
你们之前在赫尔曼德
You guys have been in...in Helmand?
那边怎么样
What's it like there?
赫尔曼德 真他妈的糟糕 兄弟
Helmand? Fucking...horrible, mate.
我们队有两个人 上个月腿被炸飞了
Two of our boys last month got their legs blown off.
路边炸弹
IED.
你们承受着这么大的风险 军队肯定给你们一大笔工资吧
Wow, the Army must be paying you a fortune to take those kinds of risks?
兄弟 我在兰开夏倒垃圾挣得都比这多
Mate, I'd make more money emptying bins back in Lancashire.
但你们接受过专业训练
But you're highly trained men.
你们应该挣更多钱
You should be making a lot more money.
你也觉得
You reckon?
如果我告诉你们 我有个朋友愿意付一万英镑
What if I told you a friend of mine would pay ten thousand British pounds...
甚至一万五千英镑
maybe even fifteen...
雇你们帮他解决一个问题 怎么说
for you to take care of a problem he has.
什么样的问题
What kind of problem?
他想让一个人死 加里 对不对
He wants someone killed, Gaz. Is that right?
你们为军队杀人 两者有什么区别
Well. You kill people for the Army, what's the difference?
除了我朋友会给你们一大笔钱
Except you'd be getting a lot more money.
我们替军队杀人不会进监狱
You don't go to prison killing people for the Army.
我朋友是重要人物
My friend is a... is a very important man.
-不会有风险  -总会有风险的
- There would be no risk. - There's always risk.
我朋友可能可以开价到两万
My friend might go up to twenty.
每人两万
For each of you.
这是我的名片
That's my card.
我的墨镜和你很配
My glasses suit you.
脱了继续喝
Naked bar!
我们真的对这个人是谁仍然毫无头绪吗
Do we really still have no idea who this man is?
-我们有他的指纹和DNA  -他没有档案记录
- We have his fingerprints and DNA. - There's no record of him.
-哪里都没有  -所以 这个画像就是我们现有的全部线索
- Anywhere. - So, the e-fit is basically all we've got?
没 我们还有亚历山大·杜根这条线索
No. We have Alexander Duggan.
那个死掉的狙击手
The dead sniper?
杜根和他的小队不对劲
Something is not right about Duggan and his unit.
首先 杜根的军队档案是二级绝密
First off, Duggan's army files are STRAP 2.
-肯定搞错了  -没搞错
- That must be a mistake. - No mistake.
我需要看杜根和他小队的档案
I need to see the file on Duggan and his unit.
那我们得办一个非常官僚 很烦人的手续
That'll be a very bureaucratic, which is to say, tiresome, process.
杜根曾是狙击好手 狙击王者
Duggan was an outstanding sniper. The best.
对 曾经是
Yes. Was.
-根据现有记录 只有他有能力射中那一枪  -但他死了
- He's the only man on record capable of making that shot. - But he's dead!
他去了阿富汗 然后再也没回来
He went to Afghanistan and never came back.
但是死无对证
But there's no body.
那份档案上也许有能帮到我们的信息
There could be information in that file that will help us.
我想想办法吧
Let me see what I can do.
比安卡 你今晚六点能不能抽出十分钟
Bianca, are you free at six this evening for ten minutes,
-见一下外交大臣  -可以
- to meet with the Foreign Secretary? - Yep.
卡弗在竭力审问每一个人
Carver's doing his best with his inquiries
但这整件事碍手碍脚的
but the whole thing's just getting in the way.
非常的 令人疲惫
Which is...rather tiresome.
比安卡 很高兴和你见面
Ah! Bianca. Great pleasure to meet you.
我也是
And you.
-请坐  -谢谢
- Please. - Thank you.
我今早收到首相发给我的信息
So, erm, I received a WhatsApp message from the PM this morning
有个链接 是一段你在塔林的视频
with a link to the clip of you in Tallinn.
配文是 全英第一
And he wrote, "Best of British!"
这么看来 我们在某些方面
So, it seems that there are still some things
还是世界一流的
in which we are world class,
重要的是 让全世界都知道了
and importantly the world knows it.
伊莎贝尔告诉我 你想看一份二级绝密文件
So, Isabel was telling me you want to have a look at a STRAP 2 file?
是的
That's right.
你觉得它能帮你找到豺狼
Because you think it'll help you find the Jackal?
-是的  -听说你魅力十足
- Yes. - Rumour has it that you can be charming.
你能否对国防部施展一下美男计
I thought you might like to use those charms on the MoD?
当真如此吗
Did you indeed.
那样的话 我就要欠尼克一个人情了
Well, it would mean owing Nick a favour, and that's not...
我不喜欢这样
Well it's not an ideal situation to be in.
确实
No.
那大概也比乌达查被一个
Though perhaps a better situation than if UDC were killed
以前在英军部队当过兵的职业杀手杀了
by an assassin who turns out to be ex-British Army,
而事后才爆出我们得到了消息却置之不理 要好一些
and it's later revealed we had information we didn't act on.
那些内部调查最烦人了
Those internal inquiries are always such a bore.
的确
Quite.
好吧 行 我去找尼克
OK, yup. All right, I'll talk to Nick.
好了 我要去剧院了
Right, I've got to get to the theatre so um...
-还有别的事吗  -目前没有了
- Anything else? - That's it for now. I think.
好
Good.
-好吧 观剧愉快  -谢谢
- OK, well, enjoy your play. - Thank you.
大卫·海尔是英国著名剧作家
大卫·海尔的剧 观剧能愉快才怪
It's David Hare. Of course I'm not gonna bloody enjoy it.
安卡拉  土耳其
我们的声音
为我们的人民服务
我朋友对你们干的活很满意
My friend is very pleased with your work.
总理强调强硬外交政策
巴尔扎尼总是惹事生非
Barzani was a big troublemaker.
在他的报纸上胡编乱造
Always telling lies in his newspaper.
说实话
You know, frankly,
我朋友不信你们能成功
my friend wasn't sure if you'd be able to do it.
要知道 巴尔扎尼特别警惕 身边总是围着一堆保镖
Know Barzani was a very paranoid man. Always lots of guards.
他很少露面 但你们做到了
He hardly ever showed his face. But you did it.
你们真是厉害
You are the best.
我朋友希望你们能再帮他一点忙
My friend is hoping you might be available to look at something else for him.
-多少钱  -他出手大方
- How much? - He's a very generous man.
同时 树敌不少
He also has...a lot of enemies.
当然 我们会提供所有后勤
And we'd provide all the logistics of course,
机票 装备 住宿 日常花销 文件 都由我们出
travel, equipment, housing, expenses, documentation, everything.
听着倒不错
Sounds fucking great.
但我服役期还有六年
But I've still got six years to serve.
杜根还有三年
Duggan's got three.
如果我们擅离职守 宪兵会满世界找我们
If we go AWOL, the military police will be looking everywhere for us.
他们可不是闹着玩的
Those fuckers don't fuck about.
好吧 如果你们改变主意 随时给我打电话
Well, if you change your mind. You have my number.
行
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
突发新闻 警方正在寻找该男子
如果你有该男子的任何线索 请拨打以下号码
努丽娅 快来 快过来
Come here! Here, here, here! Nuria! Quick!
你在喊什么
What's all the shouting?
快看电视
Look at this...
看
Look.
是查尔斯吧
lt's Charles, isn't it?
是他吗
lt's him?
突发新闻 警方正在寻找该男子
如果你有该男子的任何线索 请拨打以下号码
也可能是其他人
lt could be anyone.
得了吧 就是他 你自己清楚
Come on, it's him, you know it's Charles.
你之前说他去了塔林
You said he went to Tallinn?
这个叫豺狼的杀手恰巧也在塔林
This Jackal killer is in Tallinn.
努丽娅
Nuri?
努丽娅 你知道查尔斯现在在哪吗
Nuria do you know where Charles is?
-嘿  -你还在塔林吗
- 'Hey!' - Are you still in Tallinn?
不在 我设法逃走了
'No, no. I managed to get out.
那里一片混乱 你还好吗
It was absolute carnage there, though. Are you alright?'
西班牙电视上有一张通缉令
There's a picture on TV here in Spain.
警察在找一个人
A man the police are looking for.
你说的那个我也看到了
'Yeah, I think I've seen the same one.'
阿尔瓦罗觉得那人是你
Alvaro thinks it's you.
好吧
OK.
你必须告诉你弟弟 别跟别人提及此事
You must tell your brother that he cannot repeat that to anyone.
听到了吗 这很重要
'Do you hear me? This is important.
天哪 真的是你
My God, it's all true.
你告诉阿尔瓦罗 千万不要和别人说那人是我 懂吗
You tell Alvaro that he cannot repeat what you just said to anybody, am I clear?
警察会找过来吗
Will the police come here?
不会 他们完全没有理由过去
'No, they have absolutely no reason to come.
听我说 努丽娅 你非常安全
You listen to me, Nuria, OK. You are completely safe.
没人知道我是谁 也不知道我住在哪
No one knows who I am. They don't know where I live.
你 卡利托斯 你家人 都是安全的
You, Carlito, the family. You're all safe.
但你得告诉你弟 他必须把嘴闭紧
But you tell your brother that he must not say a word.'
-你搞什么 查尔斯  -这很重要
- What the fuck, Charles? - 'No, this is important.
你告诉你弟 他必须保密
You tell your brother he can't say a word.'
你明天还能回来吗
Are you still coming tomorrow?
能
'Yes, I am.
-我明天下午就到家  -你最好回来
- I'll be there in the afternoon.' - You'd better be here.
因为
Because now...
我受够了
...this ends!
我他妈要知道真相
I want the fucking truth!
供暖公司经理 加里 和他的妻子 杰西
'Heating firm manager, Gary, and his wife, Jess,
两年前买下了这块地皮
bought this plot of land two years ago.
克服诸多规划困难后
After overcoming several planning obstacles,
这项伟大工程开始动工 他们的梦想之家逐步成形
work began on this extraordinary project. And their dream home began to take shape.
妈
Mum?
贾思敏
Jaz?
我不知道你会来
I didn't know you were...
稍等一下
Just stand back a second.
嗨 快进来
Hi. Come in.
我们能就站在这说吗
Can we just talk out here?
屋里没别人 就我
There's no one here. It's just me.
宝贝 站在外面多冷
Look, we can't stand in the cold, my love.
进来说吧 好吗
Can you just come in, please?
我好想你
God, I've missed you so much.
想喝茶吗
Do you want a tea or something?
-真的很冷呢  -我没事
- You know, it's really cold. - I'm good.
你救了乌达查一命吗
Did you save UDC's life?
我和其他人一起
I...was part of a team.
我的所有朋友都觉得他会改变世界
All my friends think he's gonna change the world.
是吗 你也这么认为吗
Oh? Do you?
他为我们这一代人做了很多 所以 可能吧
Well, he does a lot for our generation so...maybe.
可能
Maybe.
你真的要离开我们吗
Are you really leaving us?
什么
What?
我不是要离开你们 我永远不会那么做
I am not leaving. I wouldn't. I would never do that.
那为什么我们不能回来 一起住
Then why aren't we back here? Together?
我得想想 怎么才能最好地保护你和家人
I...need to work out how best to protect you and our family.
懂吗
OK.
我得保护好你们
I need to...I need to... make sure I get that right.
那天晚上来这的那个男人呢
So what happened to the man who came here that night?
他进监狱了 他伤害不到你了
He's in prison. He can't hurt you.
我不觉得他真想伤害我
I don't think he really wanted to hurt me.
他只是为他女儿的事伤心 我挺可怜他的
He was just upset about his daughter. And I feel sorry for him.
贾思敏 别这么想
Oh, don't. Don't Jaz, honestly.
-他不是好人  -妈 可是他女儿死了
- He's not a good man. - But, Mum. His daughter died.
她的死和你有关系吗
Did you have something to do with her death?
没有
No.
我知道你救人 那是好事
I know you save people. And that's a good thing.
但有时
Sometimes...
你可能迫不得已做一些不太好的事
..you might have to... do some other things that you might not want to do.
没有 贾思敏
No, Jaz.
我只做好事 不做坏事
I...I only do good things, no bad things.
知道吗
OK?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
妈 看着我
Mum, just look at me.
我确定
Yes.
纳吉布·汗是塔利班的战地指挥官
Najib Khan is a Taliban field commander.
危险人物
A very dangerous individual.
他下山来参加亲戚的婚礼
He's come down from the hills to attend the wedding of a cousin.
这个机会错过就太可惜了
It's too good an opportunity to miss.
但我们需要谨慎行事 不要搞大动静
But we need to tread carefully, no fireworks.
我们要活捉他
We need him alive.
杜根和加里负责掩护
Duggan and Gary will be watching over.
把车准备好
Prepare the vehicles to move.
杜根 加里 还有罗尼 你们坐第一辆车
Duggan, Gary and er...Ronnie, you're in the first vehicle.
我 康拉德 杰森坐第二辆
I'll be in the second one with Conrad and Jason.
记得别来硬的 要留活口
Remember this is a soft knock. Let's take him alive.
-遵命  -祝你们好运
- Yes, sir. - Good luck.
右臂
别啊 不能用右臂可怎么办
Oh, no. What am I gonna do without my right arm?
兄弟 你可以先找个女朋友
You can start by getting yourself a girlfriend, buddy.
去你的 杜根
Fuck you, Duggan.
或者找只羊
Or a goat.
我看到有些姑娘在那放羊呢
I've seen some fetching goats out there.
-你看到了  -你不也看到了
- Yeah. Seen 'em! - Yeah, you've seen 'em.
就是简单的抓人 抓完就走 别乱来 懂吗
Simple extraction. In and out, no messing, yeah?
豺狼
幻影
侦查就位 我们掩护你们
Overwatch in position, we've got you covered.
收到 准备进入
'Copy that. Entering now.
冷静应对 服从命令
Calm but firm, boys.
你好
Alsalam ealaykum.
放下你们的武器
Put your weapons down.
放下
Down!
朋友
Friend.
我们不是来找麻烦的 但你们要放下武器
We don't want any trouble, but you have to lower your weapons.
放下
Down!
我们想进去
We are going in there.
慢慢来
Easy does it
重要首领 头子 在里面
Important chief. Big man. Inside...
对 我们就是来找他的
Yeah, that's who we're here for.
-英国朋友  -别让我再说一遍
- Friend of British. - I am not gonna tell you again!
他们看起来有点儿不爽
They don't look happy.
把武器放下 快点
Put your fucking weapons down, now!
-据点上面的狙击手  -看到了
- Shooter above compound. - Seen.
他在瞄准了 我们怎么办
He's lining up. What do we do?
副省长在里面 你们不能带着武器进去
The Deputy Governor's in there. You can't go in armed.
-要等吗 看看他开不开枪  -不用 他已经准备动手了
- Do we wait? See if he opens fire? - No, it's on us.
赶紧把武器放下
Put your fucking weapons down now!
交火
Contact!
糟了
Shit!
有火箭筒
RPG!
瓦尔特又他妈发疯了
Walter's fucking lost it again!
停火
Cease fire!
原本是一场婚礼
It was a wedding.
行动
Move!
上
Go!
任务有点搞砸了
Well, that went a bit fucking west.
我们得收拾一下
We need to make this look proper.
铁锤十四 这里是幻影一零阿尔法
Hello, Hammer fourteen, this is Phantom One Zero Alpha.
网格坐标 37565679
Grid location three, seven, five, six, five, six, seven, nine.
186度 我们遭到火力压制
One, eight, six degrees. We are pinned down and under fire.
请求在烟雾标记处投放一枚联合制导攻击武器
Request one joint direct attack munitions JDAM. On my smoke.
完毕
Over.
-收到 幻影  -准备上车 咱们撤退
- 'Copy Phantom.' - Ready up the cars! Let's get out of here!
你们都看到那些火箭筒了
You all saw the RPGs.
是吧 谁都不准把这里发生的事说出去
Right? No one says anything about what happened here today.
武器已发射 预计五分钟后击中目标
'Weapons away inbound five mikes.
请迅速撤离 完毕
Exfil that position fast. Over.'
豺狼
这里是幻影一零阿尔法
From Phantom One Zero Alpha.
收到 正在撤离
Copy that, withdrawing from contact now.
-上车吧 混蛋  -滚蛋
- Get in there, you fucker! - Come on, you fucker.
这可不光彩 一团糟
That wasn't clean. That was a mess.
韦克菲尔德监狱  英国
谢谢你同意见我
Thank you for agreeing to see me.
我的荣幸 比安卡
My pleasure. Bianca.
拉里 你怎么样
How you doing, Larry?
别误会 这是真诚问候
No. Genuine question.
-你还撑得住吗  -你向我承诺的那些
- How you holding up? - Yeah, see when you made me those promises,
是真心的吗 有哪怕一瞬间吗
did you actually mean them? You know even for a minute?
我其实能理解 那就是你的做风
I can understand that. It's what you do.
你利用我女儿接近我老婆
You used my daughter to get to my wife.
通过我老婆接触我 又利用我找我弟
Used my wife to get to me, used me to get to my brother.
相当精彩
Fair play.
只是那些人现在都死了
Except all those people are dead now.
全都是拜你所赐 比安卡
That's some trail of woe you've left behind, Bianca.
拉里 我没有杀害艾莉森 是你干的
Larry, I didn't kill Alison. You did.
是啊 我杀了艾莉森
Yeah, I killed Alison.
我还杀过很多人
I've killed a lot of people.
他们大部分都该死
Most of them deserved it.
而且我也利用别人来达成目的
And I've used people to get what I want.
和你做的如出一辙
Which is exactly the same as what you do.
我是个混蛋 道德沦丧
Now, I'm bad. I'm rotten.
但你也一样
But so are you.
我说得不对吗
Tell me I'm a liar.
听着
Listen...
我每天都会想起艾玛和艾莉森
I think about Emma and Alison every single day.
我非常 非常抱歉
And I'm truly, genuinely sorry.
所以我想要见你
That's why I wanted to see you.
当面跟你道歉
To tell you that I am sorry.
你这个口是心非的混蛋
You don't know what sorry means.
比安卡 你比我更变态
You're more twisted than what I am, Bianca.
医生
Medic!
快叫医生
Medic now!
去叫医生
Medic!
叫救护车 请你退后
Call an ambulance! Move back, please.
退后
Back!
他可能杀了二十多个人
That man probably killed 20-odd people,
包括他的妻子
including his wife.
我手上真的沾了他的血
I've literally got blood on my hands.
来 我可什么都没看见
Come here. I don't see anything.
比安卡
Bianca...
这栋楼里的每个人 都未曾预料到自己要做某些事
Everyone in this building has done stuff they never thought they would ever do.
-嗯  -听我说
- Yep! - Look.
如果有人告诉你 街上有个人
If you're told that some guy down the street
很危险 你必须将他解决
is a clear and present danger and has to be neutralised,
这很容易 是不是 你不认识他 只管解决他就好
it's easy, isn't it? You don't know him, you just do it.
是的
Yes.
如果那是你邻居 就会比较困难
If it's your next-door neighbour, it's a bit harder.
但是我们必须去做
But we do what has to be done.
但 怎么说呢 如果那是你母亲
But what if it's... I...I don't know. Your mum.
糟糕的举例
Bad example.
-糟糕的举例  -好吧 很中肯
- Bad example. - OK, fair enough.
但你知道我在说什么 这份工作很复杂
But you get my point. This job is complicated.
我们必须牢记初心
We have to remember why it is we do it.
-初心是什么  -保护他人
- Remind me. - To protect people.
保护他人
To protect people.
如果我告诉你 你可以去二号会议室看亚历山大·杜根的档案
Would it help cheer you up if I told you they had Alexander Duggan's file
你能振作起来吗
waiting for you in Conference Room 2?
真的吗
Seriously?
当然会
Yes, yes, it would help.
外交大臣提供的
Courtesy of the Foreign Secretary.
不知道你和伊莎贝尔对他说了什么 总之凑效了
Whatever you and Isabel said to him, it worked.
谢谢
Thank you.
-恐怕不行  -什么
- I'm afraid not. - What?
他们允许你和文森查阅 但有条件
You and Vince are authorised to read. There are conditions.
不能将文件带出会议室 我也不能
This file doesn't leave this room, and neither do I.
开始吧 你们得签这个
Starting now. And you have to sign this.
太离谱了
This is fucking mad.
请在底部签名
Sign at the bottom, please.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thanks very much.
谢谢
Thank you.
亚历山大·詹姆斯·戈登·杜根
Alexander James Gordon Duggan
以军官候补生的身份在桑赫斯特皇家军事学院接受训练
joins Sandhurst as an officer cadet
大家认为他能赢得荣誉之剑
and is tipped to win the Sword of Honour
但后来 他以普通士兵身份加入了伞兵团
until he walks out and joins the Paras as a private.
他的教官这样评价他
His depot instructor notes on his appraisal,
杜根在成为空降兵的过程中
Duggan displays a ruthless determination
展现出冷硬的决心
to become a paratrooper.
他在皮尔布赖特参加了狙击手训练
He does the sniper course at Pirbright HDPRCC.
在沃明斯特参加了狙击指挥官训练
Attends the sniper commander's course at the Sniper Wing at Warminster.
作为王牌狙击手加入了先导排
Joins the Pathfinder Platoon as their top sniper.
先后被派遣到北爱尔兰 挪威 科索沃 塞拉利昂 伊拉克
Deploys to Northern Ireland, Norway, Kosovo, Sierra Leone, Iraq.
之后去了阿富汗
And then Afghanistan.
他是一支秘密特种部队的成员
He was part of a covert Special Forces unit.
他们负责突袭 逮捕 刺杀塔利班领导人
They carried out raids, arrests and assassinations of Taliban leaders.
2013年4月23日 这支部队在赫尔曼德开展行动
On April 23rd, 2013, the unit was on an operation in Helmand.
他们前去消灭一位臭名昭著的塔利班领导人
They were on their way to eliminate a notorious Taliban leader when...
结果整支队伍丧生于一场大爆炸
..the entire unit was wiped out by a massive explosion.
所以
So...
杜根死了吗
Duggan's dead?
我
I just...
不知道
I don't know.
已故 已故 已故
已故 麦克·鲍德温队长 已故 已故 已故 已故
不太对劲
Something's not right.
停车
Wait. Stop!
停 停 停
Stop, stop, stop!
-右上方  -嗯
- Up on the right. - Yep.
怎么了
What's going on?
你看那个土丘 上面有东西
You see that mound, there's something on the top of it.
简易爆炸装置吗
IED?
我看一眼
Let's have a look.
确实不太正常
Yeah, that does not look proper.
四点钟方向有动静
Movement at four o'clock!
全方位警戒
360 cover!
文件给我吧 欧斯
I'll take the file, Osi.
哈尔克罗 这边请 我们得谈谈
This way, Mr Halcrow. We need to talk.
有发现吗
Anything?
没有
No.
什么都没有 你个蠢货
There's fuck all there, you dickhead.
我跟你说 我真的看到了
I'm telling you, I saw something.
你怎么看
What'd you reckon?
我们不能就这样傻站在这里
Well, we can't just stand around here like a bunch of knobheads.
我们有任务 必须得走
We've got a job. We have to move.
-我去看看吧  -好
- I'm happy to take a look. - Yeah, OK.
康拉德 你跟杜根去
Conrad, go with Duggan.
不用 加里和我去
No, I'll take Gary with me.
加里 走
Come on, Gary.
你愿意去排爆 我没意见
Oi, you wanna check for IEDs, I'm happy for you, mate.
但你为啥叫我一起去
Why the fuck do I have to come with you?
喂
Oi!
-走吧  -我真是谢谢你
- Come on. - Thanks for fuck all, mate.
你掩护我行吗
Will you cover me?
小心点 哥们
Careful, mate.
你觉得这儿有东西吗
Think it's a come-on?
你在干啥 你个疯子
What you doing, you fucking loon?
我从这儿开始排查
I'm gonna feel my way from here.
三轮车
Fucking tricycle!
搞什么
Oh, what the fuck.
上车
Mount up.
走了 哥们 走吧
Come on, mate, let's go.
杜根
Duggan.
怎么回事
What the fuck!
刚才是什么情况
What the fuck just happened?
-我们得走了  -去哪
- We need to go. - Go where?
别人找不到我们的地方
Where they can't find us.
也许你奔波已久
♪ You may run on for a long time
我却要说 上帝要置你于死地
♪ Let me tell you that God's gonna cut you down
我的上帝开口 声音如此甜美
♪ My God spoke, he spoke so sweet
我以为那是天使的脚步匆匆
♪ I thought I heard the shuffle of angel's feet
他一手轻抚我额头
♪ He put one hand upon my head
全能之神啊 让我告诉你他的话
♪ Great God Almighty, let me tell you what he said
也许你奔波已久
♪ You may run on for a long time
奔波已久
♪ Run on for a long time
我却要说 上帝要置他于死地
♪ Let me tell you that God's gonna cut him down
去告诉那些虚伪小人
♪ Go tell that long tongue liar
去告诉那些午夜骑士
♪ Go and tell that midnight rider
告诉上帝 谨防暗箭
♪ Tell the God that looked around at the back biter
告诉他 上帝要置他于死地
♪ Tell him that God's cut him down
♪ Tell him that God's cut him down ♪